两周前
Two weeks ago,
一个隐形穹顶罩住了切斯特磨坊镇
an invisible dome crashed down on Chester's Mill,
使我们与世隔绝
cutting us off from the rest of the world.
为什么穹顶会在这里  以后还会有什么谜团
Why the dome is here or what mysteries lie ahead,
我们依然一无所知
we still don't know.
每天它都考验我们的极限
Every day it tests our limits,
激发我们内心最善和最恶一面
bringing out the best and the worst in us.
有人说我们会永远困在这里
Some say we'll be stuck here forever,
但我们会一直奋力寻找出路
but we will never stop fighting to find a way out.
丽贝卡·佩恩觉得切斯特磨坊镇
Rebecca Pine thinks Chester's Mill
维持不了多久全镇居民的供给
can't sustain itself for much longer,
她和吉姆想通过人口调查
and she and Jim want to use the census
来决定大家的生死
to decide who lives and who doesn't.
猪流感就是他们的灭绝计划
That pig virus is their extermination plan.
对  而且她不知道那效力有多大
Yeah, and she doesn't know how strong it is.
离我远点
Get away from me!
你想杀了我们
You tried to us all!
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
她要跟你一起进监狱
She's joining you in jail.
你打算怎么对付我们
What are you gonna do to us?
明天我们会召开镇民大会
Tomorrow we'll have a town meeting
人们来决定你们的命运
and the people can decide your fate.
你是来放我出去的
You came to set me free.
我妈妈说你有答案  我想知道
My mother said you had answers; I want them.
是这个  是吗
This is it, right?
抱歉  孩子
Sorry, kid.
那些是手指印
Those are the fingertips of a hand--
似乎安琪也留下了一点凶手的战利品
Looks like Angie got a piece of whoever did this to her.
你觉得呢  菲尔
What do you say, Phil?
我能信任你吗
Can I count on you?
我就是梅兰妮·克洛斯
I am Melanie Cross.
我应该是死在了这里
And I think this is where I died.
天啊  我们得去帮她
Oh, my God, we have to help her.
我们帮不了了
I don't think we can.
-太晚了  -她要死了
- It's too late. - She's dying.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
你刚才在呻吟
You were moaning.
做恶梦了吗
Nightmare?
不是  只是普通的梦
No. Just a dream.
并没有醒来以后看到你俩站在我面前那么恐怖
Not as scary as waking up to you two standing over me.
我们这几天都没有睡好
None of us sleep very well these days.
我需要找到山姆·维多
I need to find Sam Verdreaux.
查清楚我死的那晚到底发生了什么
Find out what really happened the night I died.
我知道你想要答案
I know you want some answers,
但我们答应芭比了
but we promised Barbie
在他跟茱莉亚谈完之前我们不会做任何事
we wouldn't do anything until after he talks to Julia.
我需要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
我得去找我们的神秘女孩
I need to find our mystery girl.
她昨晚没回家
She didn't come home last night.
梅兰妮跟乔和诺莉待在一起
Melanie stayed with Joe and Norrie.
梅兰妮  你怎么知道她的名字
Melanie? How do you know her name?
说来话长
It's a long story.
你不会刚好知道山姆在哪里吧  对吗
You wouldn't happen to know where Sam is, would you?
他刚刚离开
He just left.
我们通宵工作来着
We were up all night, working.
你找山姆干什么
Why are you looking for Sam?
因为我认为他一直认识梅兰妮
Because I think he's known who Melanie is all along.
告诉我所有的事
All right, tell me everything.
孩子们在学校年鉴上找到了她的照片
The kids found her picture in the school yearbook.
-那她是这里的学生吗  -曾经是
- So, she's a student here? - Was.
1988年的
In 1988.
我知道
I know.
我还在消化这一切
I'm still processing all of this.
她还知道乔和诺莉在哪里找到的迷你穹顶
She also knows exactly where Joe and Norrie found the mini-dome.
怎么知道的
How?
25年前  她和她的三个朋友发现一颗陨石
25 years ago, she and three of her friends found a meteorite
里面有颗蛋  迷你穹顶也刚好在
in exactly the same spot in the woods
树林里的那个位置
with an egg inside.
梅兰妮说当她找到它时
Melanie said that when she found it,
她想要保护它  但其他人变得暴躁起来
that she wanted to protect it, and the others got violent.
然后  她的一个朋友杀死了她
And then, one of her friends killed her.
她不知道是谁
She's not sure who.
她的三个朋友都是谁
Who were the three friends?
波琳·维多  莱尔·夏姆利
Pauline Verdreaux, Lyle Chumley
还有山姆
and Sam.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
这在切斯特磨坊镇是常有的事
This is just par for the course for Chester's Mill.
我们需要谈谈另一天发生的事
And we need to talk about what happened the other day.
关于你支持吉姆和丽贝卡的灭绝计划的事吗
About your supporting Jim and Rebecca's extermination plot?
你怎么会觉得我真会支持呢
How could you think that I would actually do that?
-因为我当时在场  -我那是在听他们说
- Because I was there. - I was listening
才能知道他们到底要做些什么
so I could make sure that I knew exactly what they were up to,
才可以去阻止他们
so I could stop them.
我让吉姆看着我的眼睛
I made Jim look me in the eye
向我承诺他不会做任何事
and promise me that he wasn't gonna do anything.
我才不信
I don't know that I believe that.
如果你想要把我当成坏人
If you want to think that I'm the bad guy,
随你
then fine.
做好山姆·维多更糟糕的准备吧
Be prepared to think far worse of Sam Verdreaux.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：加森   送小孩   圈圈   Michael   面条   冰蓝
校对：冰蓝     时间轴：腿毛   猫   萌
后期：冰蓝     总监：冰蓝
你他妈在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
试着找你背着我藏起来的东西
Trying to find what you've been hiding from me.
比如我妈妈的日记
Like my mom's journal.
我没有  小詹姆斯
I don't have it, Junior.
有人把它偷走了
Someone stole it.
莱尔偷的
That was Lyle.
莱尔在监狱里
Lyle's in jail.
直到我偷偷把他放了出来
He was until I snuck him out.
他告诉我说我妈妈的日记里有预言
He told me my mom's journal had predictions in it,
比如谁会杀了安琪
like who was gonna kill Angie.
你有什么发现
What'd you find out?
我还没查到  他袭击了我
I didn't get that far. He attacked me,
然后带着日记跑了
and he ran off with it.
他不想让我看到里面的内容
He didn't want me to see what was in it.
所以一定是他杀了安琪  对吗
So he must have killed Angie, right?
他总是有点疯癫
He always has been a little nuts.
日记中的好多页没了
Pages missing from the journal.
我觉得如果我找到了
I thought if I'd find it,
就能知道他去了哪里
I'd be able to figure out where he's going
或者他接下来要做什么
or what he's gonna do next,
或者他要逃到哪里
or where he's run off to.
你什么也找不到
You won't find anything.
如果莱尔伤害到别人  就是我的错
If Lyle hurts somebody else, it's on me.
那么我们一起阻止他
So we'll stop him together.
我不该相信他  不管我妈妈说什么
I should have never trusted him, no matter what my mom said.
你妈妈让你相信莱尔吗
Your mother told you to trust Lyle?
在她死前
Before she died?
两天前  她给我发了一封电邮
Two days ago, she sent me an e-mail.
她还活着
She's alive.
她在外面的某处
She's out there somewhere.
我还在想你们俩何时会出现
I was wondering when you two would show.
我们在找卡罗琳和孩子们
Yeah, we're just looking for Carolyn and the kids.
他们在后面
In the back.
我可以给你们拿点麦片  土司和茶
I can bring you cereal, toast and tea.
食物是哪来的
Where'd you get all the food?
地下室的秘密储粮
Secret store in the basement.
安琪告诉我的  愿她安息
Angie told me about it, God rest her soul.
我们都在等着开镇民大会  茱莉亚
Oh, and we're all waiting for the town meeting, Julia.
如果她在这里用餐  我就离开
If she's eating here, I ain't.
镇里来去自由
Hey, it's a free town.
大个儿吉姆入狱后就不自由了
Not since Big Jim went to jail.
我没听错吧  格雷格
I hear you right, Greg?
你要跟那个试图用病毒
You throwing your lot in with the guy
杀死所有人的家伙站在一边吗
who tried to murder everyone with that virus of his?
吉姆才没有用什么病毒
Jim wasn't caught with no virus.
这是陷害
It was a set-up, all right,
-这样她就能掌权  让他受审  -别碰我
- so she can take over and put him on trial. - Get off!
够了
Whoa, whoa, whoa! That's enough. Hey,
退后
just back off.
你的审判
This trial of yours?
最好做出正确的裁决
It better reach the right verdict.
你找到莱尔了吗
Did you find Lyle?
还没有
Not yet.
小詹姆斯和我整夜都在镇里找他
Junior and I spent all night combing the town for him,
但一无所获
but no sign of him.
我应该出去找他
I should be out there looking for him.
这里是个火药桶
This place is a powder keg.
不  我要你们三个今天低调行事
No, I want the three of you to lie low today.
审判必须快点开始
This trial has to happen soon.
我打算在镇民大会上
I'm planning on reading the charges
宣读吉姆和丽贝卡的罪名
against Jim and Rebecca at the town meeting.
他们还需要代理律师
They'll need representation, too.
希望你能帮忙
Which is where you come in, I hope?
老妈当大个儿吉姆的律师
Mom as Big Jim's lawyer?
他绝对要被判有罪了
He's so totally guilty.
所有人都应得到公正的审判
Everyone deserves a fair trial.
我猜我应该去
Well, I guess I'll go,
陪我的新客户去市政厅了
uh, escort my new clients to the town hall.
那里见  茱莉亚
I'll see you there, Julia.
谢谢  卡罗琳
Thank you, Carolyn.
我告诉了茱莉亚
I filled Julia in
我们发现的关于梅兰妮的所有事
on everything that we found out about Melanie,
但是只有茱莉亚知道
but only Julia.
我很抱歉昨天没有和你在一起  梅兰妮
I'm really sorry that I wasn't there with you yesterday, Melanie.
我现在知道自己是谁了
I know who I am now,
但我为什么会回来
but why am I back?
我不知道  但一定有原因
I don't know, but there is a reason.
我保证我会查出来
I promise I'll find out what it is.
山姆会去市政厅
Sam will be at the town hall.
芭比和我会跟他谈谈
Barbie and I will talk to him.
好吗  但是他说得对
All right, but he's right.
你们留下  好吗
You kids stay. Okay?
让我们先问出答案
Let us get some answers first.
我刚发现我死了
I just found out I died.
我不能坐在这里袖手旁观
I can't just sit around and do nothing.
来吧  我知道该去哪里
Come on, I know where to go.
有人吗
Anybody out there?
够了  吉姆  我头疼
Okay, enough, Jim. I've got a headache.
你头疼是吗
Oh, you got a headache, huh?
我快要在这里饿死了
I'm just about starving in here.
拜托  只过了一晚
Come on. It's only been one night.
茱莉亚保证会有审判
Julia promised a trial.
她会来找我们的
She'll come for us, okay?
对  她当然会来
Yeah, she'll come for us, all right.
然后呢
Then what?
她要绞死我们吗
She gonna hang us?
我们只是不想让大家饿死
We were just trying to keep everyone from starving to death.
现在所有人都以为我是连环杀手
Now everyone thinks I'm some sort of serial killer,
这都是你的错
and it's all your fault.
你说服我该进行你的计划
You convinced me that your plan's the right thing to do.
然后你骗了我  让我没做成
And then you... then you tricked me into not being able to do it.
我告诉你了
I told you,
病毒比我想象的更强大
the virus was stronger than I thought.
如果情况改变  你也必须改变思维
If the evidence changes, your thinking has to change.
这叫科学
It's called science.
我不在乎你怎么叫
I don't care what you call it.
现在人人都想让我们见血
Now everybody's out there for our blood.
感谢大家今天前来
Thanks, everyone, for joining me today.
我知道这周很不好过
I know it's been a rough week,
但我觉得是时候展望未来了
but I think it's time for us to focus on our future.
大个儿吉姆那个混蛋呢
Where's that piece of crap-- Big Jim?
他和丽贝卡·佩恩将被提审
He and Rebecca Pine will be arraigned
并在陪审团面前审判
and tried in front of a jury.
过程公平公正
The process will be fair and impartial.
首先我想谈谈食物情况
First, though, I'd like to talk to you about the food situation.
储粮不足了
Supplies are running low.
但是不必恐慌
But there's no need to panic.
我们可以一起克服难关
We can get through this by coming together.
所以我将发起自愿捐献食物行动
Which is why I'm initiating a voluntary food share program.
大家可以将自己的食物
People can bring whatever they have
拿到切斯特磨坊镇消防站
to the Chester's Mill fire station.
志愿者将监督分配
Volunteers will oversee distribution,
确保人人得食
insuring no one goes hungry.
你想让我放弃家人的食物吗  这太疯狂了
You want me to give up my family's food? That's crazy!
参与完全自愿
Participation is completely voluntary.
但是聚合资源
But pooling our resources
是保证每个人都吃上饭的最好方法
is the best way to insure everyone gets fed.
那个混蛋来了
There's the son of a bitch!
你为什么要杀我们  吉姆
Why'd you try to kill us all, Jim?
我做的一切  都是为了小镇
Everything I did, I did for this town.
我爱切斯特磨坊镇
I love Chester's Mill,
我会证明自己的清白
and I'll prove that I'm innocent of these charges.
祝你好运  亲爱的
Good luck, honey.
今天  我们在此审讯吉姆·雷尼和丽贝卡·佩恩
Today, we arraign Jim Rennie and Rebecca Pine
-主要罪名有以下几项  -都是谎言
- on the following charges. - It's all lies!
你才该接受审讯  不是他
You deserve to be on trial, not him!
-对  -对
- Yeah! - Yeah!
-等一下  -吉姆  告诉我们你干了什么
- Wait a minute. - Jim, Tell us what you did.
大家先冷静  听她说完
Folks, calm down and let her speak.
大家冷静  退后  先让她说
Calm down! Back up. Let her speak.
菲尔  你得先把他们带走
Phil, you got to get them out of here!
大个儿吉姆  丽贝卡  我们走
Big Jim, Rebecca, let's go.
有枪
Gun!
他死了
He's dead.
穹顶之下  第二季第五集
我不敢相信波琳竟然还活着
I just can't believe Pauline's still alive.
为什么她要让我们以为她去世这么久了
Why would she let us believe that she was dead for so long,
-即使她是想保护我们  -你当时还小
- even if she was protecting us? - You were a kid.
可能你需要保护  但我不需要
Maybe you needed protecting. I didn't.
波琳开始说什么穹顶的事时
When Pauline started ranting about some dome,
我就不相信她了
I stopped believing in her.
这让她崩溃了
It crushed her.
但到底是什么人
But what kind of person
才会让自己的哥哥和儿子为她哀痛了十年
lets her brother and her son spend a decade mourning,
而自己却在那儿给疯子前男友寄明信片
while she sends postcards to her insane ex-boyfriend?
还不提醒我们真正要死去的人是谁
And not warning us about the people who were really gonna die,
比如安琪
like Angie.
如果我能联系上她
If I could just get to her,
事情肯定不会到这个地步
things would be different.
她肯定会告诉我所做之事是否正确
She'd tell me if I was doing the right thing.
我失去妈妈时
When I lost Mom,
感觉那是最痛苦的事了
it was the worst pain ever.
直到后来又失去了安琪
Until Angie.
莱尔夺走了我最美好的东西
Lyle took the best thing I had.
要是让我找到他  我一定让他受苦
And when I find him, I'm gonna make him suffer.
然后再一枪解决了他
Right before I put a bullet between his eyes.
知道吗  孩子
You know what, kid?
可能不见的那几页日记
Maybe those missing journal pages
就是找到莱尔的关键
are the key to finding Lyle.
我到处都找过了
I've been looking for 'em everywhere.
我可能还知道一个地方
I might know a place.
要怪也只能怪你自己
You only have yourself to blame.
你和吉姆
You and Jim
还有那个人口削减计划把大家都吓坏了
and your insane reduction plan has people terrified.
所幸今天只有温德尔死了
We're lucky only Wendell died today.
否则他指不定打中谁呢
Anybody could have been hit,
可能是一个孩子  是我或者你
a kid or me or you.
谢谢
Thank you.
跟你说明一下
Just so you know...
吉姆说芭比也参与了
what Jim said about Barbie being involved,
都是假的
he wasn't.
我们背着他行动的
We went behind his back.
芭比一直相信还有其它办法
Barbie always believed there was another way.
菲尔  住手
Phil, stop.
为什么  你又管不着我
Why? I don't answer to you.
怎么管不着你  现在镇子由我负责
Yes, you do. This town put me in charge.
大个儿吉姆让我当警长
Well, Big Jim made me sheriff.
大家有危险时  我就得有所行动
And when people are at risk, I act.
你本来可以逮捕温德尔的
You could have just arrested Wendell.
芭比已经夺下他的枪了  可你却杀了他
Barbie had already disarmed him. Instead you killed him.
我做的一切都是为了保护这个小镇
I did what I had to do to keep this town safe.
温德尔死了  更不用说莱尔是在你的看管下
Wendell is dead. Not to mention the fact that Lyle escaped
逃跑了  而且现在还不知所踪
on your watch and is still on the loose.
或许你肩负不起警长这个责任
Maybe that badge is too big for you.
你想让我辞职吗
You want me to quit?
-你要逼我吗  -不  不是她
- You gonna make me? - No, not her.
是我
Me.
你们两个
You two...
真的沉迷于权力了啊
really are drunk on power, huh?
我们等着看大个儿吉姆怎么说吧
We'll see what Big Jim has to say.
如果现在做警长的是你而不是菲尔
If you'd been sheriff today instead of Phil,
-就不会有人死了  -茱莉亚
- no one would've been killed. - Julia...
你的背景很合适
You have the perfect background.
-你接受过军事训练  -几小时前
- Your military training... - A-And a few hours ago
你还指责我跟大个儿吉姆站在一边
you accused me of siding with Big Jim.
现在你又让我
Now you want me to be the person in charge
负责看管他
of keeping him locked up?
我该相信你的
I should have trusted you.
抱歉我怀疑你了
I'm sorry I didn't.
听你这么说真好
That's good to hear.
这个镇子会让人与人之间莫名其妙就反目成仇
This town just has a funny way of turning on people,
我可不想这么快就再搅入战局
and I'm not ready to jump back into the fray.
我懂
I get it.
我去找别人
I'll find someone else.
我先走了
I'm gonna go.
莱尔还在逍遥法外
Lyle's still out there.
可能他跟山姆在一起
Maybe he's with Sam.
我们会找到他们  然后让他们同处一室
Yeah, well, we'll find 'em, we'll put 'em in a room together
弄明白多年前到底发生了什么
and find out what the hell happened all those years ago.
必须如此
We have to.
为了梅兰妮
For Melanie's sake.
对
Yeah.
你碰穹顶时  它会显示什么吗
So when you touch the dome, it shows you stuff?
对
Yeah.
会显示幻象之类的东西
Like, visions, I guess.
真的吗
Seriously?
你告诉我们你死了  我们都信你了
Hey, you told us you died and we got on board.
有点团队精神好嘛
Have some team spirit.
那要是它让我看到了一些不好的事呢
But what if it shows me something awful?
你会克服的  我们都习惯了
You'll get over it. We have.
第一次碰穹顶的时候
When you touch the dome for the first time,
会有点触电的感觉
it's gonna give you a little shock.
如果你害怕了
So if you get scared,
那就放手
just let go.
看到什么了吗
What do you see?
什么都没有
Nothing.
什么也没有
Absolutely nothing.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
我已经很仔细地搜过这里了
I already searched this place pretty good.
我认识莱尔很久了
I've known Lyle a long time.
这家伙鬼把戏太多了
Guy's got a lot of tricks up his sleeve.
你看吧
Well, what do you know?
你找到了
You found 'em.
看见了吗
See?
你妈妈的确画过安琪
Your mom did draw Angie.
莱尔偷走这些是不想让我知道他干了什么
Lyle stole these to keep me from knowing what he did.
但为什么要杀安琪
But-but why kill Angie?
他几乎都不认识她
He hardly knew her.
或许跟这个有关系
Maybe this has something to do with it?
四只手
The four hands.
波琳絮絮叨叨说过很多事
Pauline ranted about a lot of things:
粉色星星  困住我们的穹顶
pink stars, a dome that would trap us
还有会保护穹顶的四只手
and the four hands that would be its protectors.
她以前经常说  四只手会撑起穹顶
She used to say, four hands will hold up the dome,
没有它们  穹顶会落下
and without them, it will fall.
是不是如果少了一只手  穹顶就会落下
Like if one of the hands wasn't around, the dome would come down?
所以莱尔才那么做
That's why Lyle did it.
他杀了安琪是为了让穹顶落下
He killed Angie to bring down the dome.
这么说安琪是四只手之一
So Angie was one of the four hands?
可能需要四个人都死才能有用
Maybe all four hands have to die for it to work.
我得走了
I have to go.
我得确定其它手没事
I have to make sure the other hands are okay.
其它手
The other hands?
你知道他们是谁吗
Do you know who they are?
是的
Yeah.
乔  诺莉和我
Joe, Norrie and me.
如果莱尔认为杀了我们四个人
If Lyle thinks that killing the four hands
就能让穹顶落下
will bring down the dome,
我们任何一个都可能是下一个目标
any one of us could be next.
吉姆
Hey, Jim?
你见过人死吗
You ever seen a man die?
我是说
I mean...
今天以前
before today?
很不幸  我见过
It's a sad fact of my life that I have, yeah.
那
So...
你是
how do you...
怎么面对的
deal with it?
我想这是大局的一部分
Just by knowing it's all part of a larger design.
温德尔的死让我们都活了下来
Wendell's death means we get to live.
我很确定这交易挺划算的
I'm sure that's a pretty good trade-off.
我之前对我们的人口计划也是这么想的
That-that's what I told myself about our population plan.
但是今天
But today...
眼睁睁看着温德尔死去
watching the life go out of Wendell...
死亡并不美丽  丽贝卡
Death isn't pretty, Rebecca.
但有时是必须的
Sometimes it's necessary.
我总是很公正地看事情
I've always looked at things clinically.
做测试  得出结果  然后采取行动
Run tests, you get results and then take action.
我觉得这让我很强大
I thought it made me strong.
但是
But?
我昨天在教堂
When I was in the church yesterday,
准备要释放病毒的时候  看到那些人
about to release the virus, and I saw those families,
让我想起了我的妈妈
it reminded me of my mom.
当我想起这样会造成很多家庭痛苦
And when I thought about causing all those families to suffer
就像她当时那样  我...
the way she did, I..
这就是你没有释放病毒的原因
That's why you couldn't do it?
如果我爸爸是对的呢
What if my dad was right
有时候一些问题真的没有答案
and sometimes there really aren't answers?
可能你爸爸是对的
Well, maybe your dad is right.
但我们不能停止尝试
That doesn't mean we stop trying.
我相信你
Look, I trusted you.
我支持你
I had your back.
我也需要你支持我
I need you to have mine.
你说得对
You're right.
我支持你
I-I do.
禁止随地吐痰
大个儿吉姆
Big Jim!
上班时喝酒啊  警长
Drinking on the job, Sheriff?
非也
Nope.
因为茱莉亚把我开除了
'Cause Julia fired me.
我得偷偷躲过我的警官们才能到这
I had to sneak past my own deputies to get in here.
好吧
Oh, well...
这样做可不对
that ain't right.
你是个好人  菲尔
You're a good man, Phil.
这个小镇最好的警长
The best Sheriff this town's ever had.
比杜克还好
Better than Duke?
还有琳达
And Linda.
你打算释放病毒
Your plan to release that virus...
你没有别的选择了  对吧
you had no other choice, right?
病毒不在我这里
I didn't even have the virus.
在丽贝卡那里
Rebecca did.
但如果我们什么都不做
But if we don't do something,
那我们谁都不能活着出去了
then none of us are gonna get out of here alive.
而现在茱莉亚让你做了她的替罪羊
And now Julia's made you her scapegoat.
恰恰在这个小镇最需要你的时候
Right when this town need you most.
等等  等等  不  不行  不能这样
Wait, wait, wait. No, no, no. Not that way.
小镇一半的人都恨我  好吧
Half this town hates me, okay?
如果你放了我  他们会
If you let me out, they're gonna...
他们会把我绑起来
they're gonna string me up.
那我们该怎么挽回
Then how do we make this right?
我们得赢得他们的心
We got to win over their hearts and minds.
还是什么都没有
Still nothing.
穹顶好像也有自己的想法
The dome kind of has a mind of its own.
可能它现在心情不好
Maybe it's not in the mood.
我们同时碰它怎么样
What if we try touching it at the same time?
我和诺莉碰的时候都有反应
Worked for me and Norrie.
因为你们不是不死怪物
Because you guys aren't some kind of undead freak.
梅兰妮  我们会想出办法的
Melanie, we're gonna figure this out.
需要多长时间
How long will that take?
我还是不明白我为什么会复活
I still have no idea why I'm back.
我们都不知道为什么被困在这个大鱼缸里
None of us know why we're trapped inside this fishbowl.
你得面对
You need to deal.
这么去想  以前你活着  然后死了
Think of it this way: you were alive, then dead,
现在又活了
now alive again.
活两次死一次挺好的
Two out of three ain't bad.
你不明白我经历的是什么
You don't know what I'm going through.
对  我不知道
No, I don't.
但我知道如果能让我妈妈复活
But I know how much I'd give
我愿意付出多少
to have my mom alive again.
我会马上用你
If it'd bring her back,
长眠于这个陨石坑来做交换
I'd trade you rotting in the bottom
只要这样能带她回来
of that crater in a heartbeat.
你知道  我一直为你说话
You know, I've defended you a lot,
但有时你真的很让人讨厌
but sometimes you're a real bitch.
梅兰妮  等等
Melanie, wait!
乔
Joe?!
诺莉  你们在家吗
Norrie?! Are you guys here?
他们也不在这
They aren't here either.
也许我们该去茱莉亚家
Maybe we should head back to Julia's.
他们也不在那
They weren't there.
也不在野蔷薇或是镇上其它地方
Or at the Sweetbriar or anywhere else in town.
会不会莱尔已经抓住他们了
What if Lyle already got 'em?
如果他伤害了他们
If he hurts them,
我永远都不会原谅我自己
I won't be able to forgive myself.
小詹姆斯  如我之前所说
Junior, like I said before,
莱尔绝不可能知道他们是四只手
there's no way Lyle could know they're part of the four hands.
你的朋友很安全
Your friends are safe.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
你得休息下平复下心情
You got to take a minute and calm down.
你这样对谁都没好处
You're no good to anyone in this state.
在穹顶降下后你就没喝过酒
You haven't had a drink since the dome came down.
你确定要这么做
You sure you want to do this?
我死去的妹妹其实还活着
My dead sister's alive,
我的外甥被一个疯子盯上了
my nephew's on some nutball's hit list.
是啊  我想要这么做
Yeah, I want to do this.
再来一杯
Another one?
梅兰妮
Melanie.
你得理解
You got to understand,
-关于诺莉  -不关她的事
- about Norrie... - It's not her,
是我自己
it's me.
我想要开心  但是
I want to be happy, but...
我感觉好孤单
I feel so alone.
而且我的存在也不正常
And I'm not normal, either.
对我你是真实存在的
You're real to me.
碰了穹顶没找到你的答案
Didn't find your answers touching the Dome, hey,
把舌头伸进他嘴里你也许就能找到答案了
maybe you'll find 'em by sticking your tongue down his throat.
实际上我一直奇怪他看上了你什么
Actually, what I'm wondering is what he sees in you,
因为你对他和其它所有人的态度都很差
since you treat him and everyone else like crap.
住手
Hey, stop.
诺莉  你没事吧
Norrie, are you okay?
别假惺惺  乔
Don't even, Joe.
你流血了
You're bleeding.
你很快也会流的
And you're about to be.
我有个主意
I've got an idea.
自愿捐献食物行动
给你
Here we go.
食物捐献行动还顺利吗
Food drive's doing well?
是啊  结果挺不错的
Yeah, I mean, it's a decent turnout,
但要想最终成功
but for this to work...
我们需要每个人的捐助
...we need everyone's help.
我去把这些放到冰箱里
I'm gonna put these in the fridge.
你能把那些箱子堆起来吗
Oh, can you stack those boxes?
好的
Yes.
卡罗琳
Carolyn.
我们走
Let's go.
茱莉亚在哪
Where's Julia?
还在里面
Still inside.
茱莉亚
Julia!
我在这里
Over here.
好了  过来
All right. Come on.
过来  这边
Come on. This way.
快走
Go!
自愿捐献食物行动
只要能安全进入楼内
As soon as it's safe to enter the building,
我们会马上评估损失  看还剩余多少
we will assess the damage, see what remains.
我剩下的所有食物都在里面
The last of my food was in there.
今晚我的家人该吃什么
What's my family supposed to eat tonight?
拜托了  我只需要大家保持冷静
Please, I just need everyone to stay calm.
别告诉我们保持冷静
Don't tell us to stay calm.
菲尔  注意你的言行
Hey, Phil, watch yourself.
我现在都不能说话了吗
So I can't even speak now?
这些人需要知道真相
These people need to know the truth.
茱莉亚的绝妙计划
Julia's big plan...
不过是为了拿走大家的食物
was just a way to take everybody's food away from them.
我什么都没拿走
I didn't take anything.
然后她把所有食物都存放在一起
Then she sticks it all in one place,
旁边还有个很久又年久失修的发动机
along with an old, beat-up generator.
如果她能事先检查下
Now, if she had bothered to check,
就会发现那电线已经磨损了
she would have seen that the wires were frayed.
大个儿吉姆就不会犯这种错误
Big Jim never would have made that mistake.
而现在我们都会挨饿了
And now we're all gonna starve.
我要拿什么喂我的孩子们
What am I gonna feed my kids?
-明天我的食物从哪来  -好了
- Where am I gonna get food tomorrow? - All-All right,
我保证我会查明到底发生了什么
I promise I will get to the bottom of what happened
并找出解决方案
and find a solution.
我只是需要大家冷静一点
I just need everyone to calm down.
这事还没完
This is not over.
你没事吧
You okay?
我们搞砸了
We're screwed.
而且菲尔说得没错  这都是我的错
And Phil's right, it's all my fault.
我没检查发电机
I didn't check the generators,
我根本没想到要检查
I didn't even think to check.
我和你的关系也搞砸了
And I screwed up with you.
我应该相信你的
I should have believed you.
你也可以这样说我  听到了吗
That goes both ways. Do you hear me?
我们都犯了错
We both made mistakes.
现在怎么办
What now?
现在我们去查出是谁引起的爆炸
Now we figure out who caused the explosion.
菲尔说是因为电线磨损
Phil said the wires were frayed.
你不相信他吗
You don't believe him?
不相信  肯定有隐情
No, there's something else going on.
就在爆炸前我发现了很多空箱子
I found a bunch of empty boxes right before that explosion.
这镇上只有一个人能做到
There's only one person in town who could do that.
我想问那个人是谁
Well, I'd ask who that was,
但答案显而易见
but it's a little obvious.
我去跟大个儿吉姆谈谈
I'll go talk with Big Jim.
真希望我知道该怎么做
I just wish I knew what to do.
不管怎么做  我好像都没法
You know, no matter what, I can't seem
让镇上大部分居民满意
to please more than half the town at a time.
别放弃
Don't give up.
有办法的  你会找到的
There's a way out of this. You're gonna find it.
好吗
Okay?
你没事吧
You okay?
抱歉
Sorry.
不  请让我来
No, please, let me.
这会显示什么
So what's this gonna show?
希望会有我们之间的不同
Hopefully if there are differences between us.
像我这样一直活着的人
A guy who's always been alive, me,
和
and...
你这样的人
someone like you.
我们不同吗
Are we different?
不确定
Uh, not sure.
有点超出了我能理解的范围
Little out of my depth here.
佩恩女士绝对能告诉我们这是什么意思
Ms. Pine would definitely be able to tell us what this means.
那我们怎么做  帮她越狱吗
So, what, we break her out of jail?
我只是随口一说
I'm just saying.
她想杀掉镇上所有的人
She tried to kill everyone in town.
我们必须做点什么
We can't just do nothing.
这血液可能说明了我的身份
This blood thing could be the answer to who I am.
是啊  或者跟别的事一样
Yeah, or end up like everything else--
毫无结果
big, fat, dead end.
哎哟
Well, well, well.
瞧瞧这是谁  你现在是警长了
Look who it is. You sheriff by now?
还是新蜂王任命你为
Or did new Queen Bee just go ahead and anoint you
切斯特磨坊镇的国王了
king of Chester's Mill?
闭嘴  吉姆
Oh, shut your mouth, Jim.
这下面可没有观众
There's no audience down here.
消防站爆炸了
There was an explosion at the firehouse.
所有储存在那里的食物都被炸毁了
All the food that was stored there's gone.
你觉得我会烧毁食物
You think I'd put this town at risk
来让这座小镇处于危险之中吗
by burning up its food supply?
那可是疯狂的新地步  芭比  就算对你而言
That's a new level of crazy, Barbie, even for you.
天啊
Oh, my God.
菲尔
Phil.
他之前来这里抱怨
He was down here grousing about
茱莉亚拿走了他的警徽  然后他提到了
Julia taking his badge and he mentioned something
食物计划的事
about the food program.
你打算这样玩啊
So that's how you're gonna play this?
你打算让菲尔背黑锅
You're gonna throw Phil under the bus?
别听我的  去问丽贝卡吧
Well, don't take my word for it, ask... ask Rebecca.
菲尔进来时我一定睡着了
I must have been asleep when Phil came in.
我什么也没听见
I didn't hear anything.
想得美  吉姆
Nice try, Jim.
好吧  你接下来要一直以为
Fine. You're gonna go about your day
爆炸是我搞的鬼
thinking I'm responsible for the explosion,
那真是...
that's, you know...
做好准备迎接
Just be ready for whatever...
菲尔接下来计划的疯狂事吧
madness Phil has planned next.
菲尔
Phil?
你在这里干什么
What are you doing in here?
确保这地方的安全
Just making sure the place is secure.
这里面有食物吗
Is there food in there?
我们没用这间房
We weren't using this room.
也许有人搬了食物
Maybe someone moved it.
为什么
Why would they?
除非他们知道会有爆炸
Unless they knew the explosion was coming?
我妈妈对所有人都撒谎了
My mom lied to everyone.
她唯一爱的人是莱尔
The only one she loves is Lyle.
我听到了  哥们
I hear you, buddy.
他们都疯了
And they're both crazy.
他们一起是疯上加疯
They're crazying it up together.
你得好好睡一觉
You got to sleep this one off.
我不想这样对你
I don't want to do this to you.
你或者安琪
You or Angie.
如果还有其它方法
If there was any other way
来摧毁穹顶  我会做的
to bring the Dome down, I'd do it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
谢谢你照顾我
Thanks for looking out for me.
我只剩你这个家人了
You're the only family I have left.
爱你  山姆舅舅
Love you, Uncle Sam.
趴下
Hey, on the ground.
马上趴下
Get on the ground right now.
不  芭比  你要这么做
No, Barbie, that's what you're going to do.
别这样  你不是这种人  菲尔
Oh, come on, this is not you, Phil.
我知道你不想伤害任何人
I know you don't want to hurt anyone.
放了她  菲尔
Drop her, Phil.
你不能再做英雄了  芭比
You're done being the hero, Barbie.
快放了她
Drop... now!
你没事吧
You all right?
是的
Yeah.
你呢
You?
现在没事了
I am now.
茱莉亚
Julia.
真是惊喜
What a nice surprise.
你有空吗
Do you have a minute?
我只是在想野蔷薇餐馆发生的事
I'm just wondering about what's happening at the Sweetbriar Rose.
我看见你在那里给大家分发食物
I see you there, feeding everyone, uh...
我想知道食物是从哪里来的
I wonder where the food is coming from.
地下储藏室
The basement pantry.
我刚看过那儿了  里面是空的
I just checked there-- it's empty.
安德莉亚  你做得很好
Andrea, you're doing an amazing job.
小镇居民活下来全是因为你
The town continues to live because of you.
我觉得我该代表大伙儿问一问
I just think I owe it to everyone to at least ask.
我得带你去看一样东西
There's something I have to show you.
天啊
Oh, my God.
这只是开始
This is just the start.
整个地下储藏室都满了
The entire basement is filled.
食物足以供给全镇居民吃几个月
There's enough to feed the whole town for a couple of months.
你从哪里弄来这么多食物
Where did you get all this food?
我去世的丈夫洛伊德的
From Lloyd, my late husband.
洛伊德称自己为活命主义者
Lloyd called himself a survivalist.
他总是能预见即将发生的糟糕事
He always saw something bad around the corner.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
他说危机来临时
Said when the crisis hit,
大家都会只为自己
it'd be every man for himself.
对不起  我没有主动站出来
I'm sorry I didn't come forward.
我只是害怕有人会偷走食物
I was just scared someone would steal it from me.
但我信任你
But I trust you.
你该使用
You should use it.
我们一起用
We'll use it together.
山姆舅舅
Uncle Sam?
我上二年级时  我妈妈画了那幅画
My mom painted that when I was in the second grade.
我拿这幅画进行展示和讲述
I brought it in for show-and-tell.
我猜你从来没看过这个吧
I'm guessing you've never seen this before.
天啊
Oh, my God.
方尖塔
The obelisk.
我有次做梦梦见过
I saw this in a dream I had.
我妈妈也在场
My mom was there, too.
1821.
那是安琪被杀之处的
That's the number of the locker at school
学校储物柜编号
where Angie got killed.
你妈妈日记的最后一页也写了
It's also in your mother's journal, on the last page.
我完全不知道这是什么意思
I had no idea what it meant.
莱尔逃跑前在日记里看到了什么
Lyle saw something in the journal before he ran off.
也许他又去储物柜那边了
Maybe he went back to the locker.
他为什么会去那里
Why would he go there?
我不知道  但这显然对他来说有意义
I don't know, but it obviously means something to him.
也许我们没找到莱尔  是因为我们还没去查看那里
Maybe we haven't found Lyle 'cause we haven't checked there.
这太棒了
This is amazing.
简直就像七月的感恩节
It's like Thanksgiving in July.
全靠茱莉亚
It's all Julia.
你从哪里弄来的食物
Where'd you get the food?
行业秘密
Trade secret.
但一定要记得感谢安德莉亚
But make sure to thank Andrea
举办了这么一场盛会
for hosting such a lovely event.
一顿好吃的不能证明什么
One nice meal doesn't prove anything.
你不是大个儿吉姆
You're no Big Jim.
我让他来决定吧
Well... I'll let him decide that.
我们在这里干什么呢
What the hell are we doing here?
等着瞧吧
Oh, just wait and see.
各位  我今早说了
Folks, I, uh, said this morning
我觉得我们镇民们
that I thought it was time for us Millers
该着眼未来了
to focus on our future.
但我觉得只有放下过去才能做到那点
But I don't think we can do that until we let go of the past.
就算是那些做过错事的人的行为
Even the actions of those who have wronged us.
大个儿吉姆和丽贝卡昨天想做的事
What Big Jim and Rebecca tried to do yesterday
没有借口
is inexcusable...
但并非不可原谅
...but it's not unforgivable.
我们可以继续保持愤怒
Now, we can stay angry,
跟对方战斗到底  或者
tear each other apart, or...
我们可以超越
we can rise above,
然后合作
and-and work together,
保证我们在穹顶之下生存下去
and ensure our survival under this dome.
我承认
I admit...
我犯过一些错
I've made some mistakes...
但那都是为了这座小镇
but all of them in service of this town.
我真的感谢茱莉亚
And I really appreciate Julia
给我机会来
giving me the chance to...
赎罪
to make amends.
你们都应该知道
And you all should know...
我觉得她管理切斯特磨坊镇管理得很好
...I think she's done a hell of a job running Chester's Mill.
好好享受吧  各位
Enjoy yourself. Enjoy yourself, folks.
享受食物吧
Enjoy the food.
我搞不懂你
You know, I don't understand you.
你一直说你站在我这边
You keep saying you're on my side,
但你肯定对我心怀不满
but it sure as hell seems like you've turned on me.
我只是想着  也许
I just think, maybe...
我们该给茱莉亚一个机会
we should give Julia a chance.
也许领导能仁慈点儿挺好的
Maybe benevolence isn't such a bad quality in a leader.
还是说仁慈会害死我们
Or it's the thing that's gonna get us all killed.
瞧瞧你做的事
Look what you did.
如果没有你的帮助  我做不成
Yeah, it wouldn't have happened without you.
我可说不好
Oh, I don't know about that.
你找到了你的警长吗
Have you... you found your sheriff yet?
怎么  你有人选吗
Why, you have someone in mind?
也许吧
I might.
之前的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about earlier.
你吻了她  乔
You kissed her, Joe.
是啊  但是...
Yeah, but...
她不是我爱的人
she's not who I love.
你才是
You are.
你当着我的面
That's your go-to...
和另一个妞儿乱搞  这就是你的借口吗
after you've macked on another chick in front of my face?
在她身上试试吧
Try it on her.
她够蠢  会上当的
She's dumb enough to fall for it.
茱莉亚  我很感受
Julia... I'm impressed.
特别是你对吉姆和我做的事
Especially with what you did for Jim and me.
我做的是对小镇有益处的事
I did what was best for the town.
我只是想道谢
I just wanted to say thank you.
茱莉亚  我们有点问题
Julia, we've got a quick question back here.
乔说你真的很聪明
Joe says you're really, really smart.
像科学家一样
Like a scientist.
谢谢
Thank you.
我有个东西想让你搞明白
I have something I want you to figure out.
关于我的
About me.
梅兰妮
乔
小詹姆斯  你在干嘛
Junior? What are you doing?
安琪就是死在了这里
This is where Angie died.
这里对凶手有意义
It meant something to the killer.
看来这玩意儿被踢坏了
Looks like the whole thing's been kicked in.
把你的手电筒给我
Give me your flashlight.
这足够让一个男人进去
It's big enough for a man.
你觉得莱尔就是消失在这里了吗
Do you think this is where Lyle disappeared to?
这是个隧道
It's a tunnel.
是啊  但是通向哪里呢
Yeah, but to where?